In the previous video we used the
spacebar to make the character jump.
But in this video we want to create a more
of a perfect jump so we're going to be able
to modify the jump force and the gravity
to make it feel a little bit more snappy.
If we head back into
our player controller script
and we never get down
to the update method.
Using a value in the advance of 10 and it's
not great to add code the value down here.
What we want to do is
add a brand new variable.
So we'll call this one
public float and we'll just
call this jump force and
we'll set that equal to 10.
Just like we had before.
Now we can copy our
jump force and replace that
times 10 in there just
so that we can control
it in the inspector.
In our start method
we want to be able to
control that gravity
to make it feel a little
bit more snappy while bringing the player
back down to where it should be originally.
So what we can do is use physics.
Which is just the physics system and we can
use dot and then we'll say gravity because
we can affect gravity
on all rigid bodies
within the scene and
we can use the star or the
multiply symbol equals a variable
that we're going to be able to use.
I'll just name that variable.
Now up here we want
to have another public
float and the variable
we're going to create.
Call this one gravity modifier and you don't
need to give it an initial value if you
don't want and I'm just
going to copy that and paste
that in here and make sure I
add a semicolon on the end.
This means we're just
going to multiply the
gravity that we have
by the gravity multiplier
and that multiplication equals is just a
shorthand way of saying physics dot gravity
equals physics dot gravity
times by gravity modifier.
So you can see we've
just removed this portion
like this and we still
have that multiplier
and that equals and we
just move it multiply over
there and we can then
get the same statement.
It just makes it a shorthand
version of doing the same thing.
If we save this script
we go back into unity
select on our player and you can see the
jump forces 10 and gravity modifier is zero.
Now if we test this
out something weird is
going to happen if we
press base you can see
that there is no gravity and
they just character flies up forever.
So if we stop that and
you can see if we set
the gravity modifier
to one this will just
be whatever gravity is times one
so that will be just its default value.
So if we press play again it
will be just like we did originally.
Just remember each
time you want to modify the
gravity modifier while
you're in game because
it only does it once
in the start method so
make sure you just stop your
game and modify that value after.
So I've stopped my
game, I've set the jump
force 15 and then modified it to and
now the jump looks a little bit snappier.
So what I want you to be able to do is go
back into your player controller script, add
yourself a public float for jump force and
gravity modifier, set the jump force equal
to 10 and then within
your start method use
physics dot gravity multiplied
equals gravity modifier.